Machel Slack Tel: 07880900087, machel_slack@yahoo.co.uk

Personal Profile

As an experienced Web / Applications Developer, my ability to communicate with clients and my meticulous approach to work, has allowed me to build and retain long lasting customer relationships which has resulted in repeat business for my own business. Additionally, my ability to rapidly acquire new software skills and to work with new technologies has allowed me to be proficient in building front-end interfaces using JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

I would now like to utilise the skills and experience gained from my seven years in Technology from University and three years developing commercially to undertake an entry level role within your company.

Work Experience

January 2016 - Present

Project Associate, UK, Sinopia Inn Limited

Having completed IT projects for the brand Sinopia Inn, I was asked to work, part time, remotely from the United Kingdom to coordinate the work needed to execute marketing and IT projects both here in London and abroad.

Duties

- Creating project documents, using existing project management templates to communicate project.objectives to all stakeholders
- Carrying out online and offline marketing campaigns, by planning, executing, monitoring and controlling work needed to be completed to meet the objectives set by the project sponsors
- Carrying out IT projects by planning, executing, monitoring and controlling work needed to be completed to meet the objectives set by the project sponsors.
- Carrying out Google Adwords campaigns, using keyword planner to design google ads to increase sales of products and services
- Carrying out Search Engine Optimisation campaigns, by creating online content relating to trending topics to increase engagement between brands and internet users.
- Carrying out Social Media Marketing campaigns by using social media listening tools to create content relating to trending topics
- Liaising with stakeholders to co develop mobile apps for commercial distribution

July 2012 - January 2016

Web / Applications Developer, UK, Unified Digital Media

I started by using Linux, Apache, MySQL and PHP (L.A.M.P) stack to design and develop responsive websites that use AngularJS to request data from MYSQL databases queried by PHP programming to improve workflow - providing staff and customers with a convenient point of sale system. I then went on to develop web applications using MongoDB, Express JS, Angular. JS and Node JS (the M.E.A.N stack) to managed client records and issue receipt on completion of transactions. I also carried out the planning of digital marketing campaigns that include the use of Bootstrap to design and develop mobile responsive Wordpress websites, to increase awareness of a hotel brand. Additionally, I have worked on projects to increase customer base, by developing smart phone applications that engages users across multiple touch points; and created opportunities for improved revenue by developing Wordpress plugins and widgets for commercial distribution.

<u>Duties</u>

- Designed and developed webpages with HTML5 and CSS3 to pique users interest
- Carried out C.R.U.D operations on SQL and noSQL databases using AngularJS RESTful web service to managed business records
- Designed and developed beta version smartphone applications, using Objective C and Java to increase audience reach

- Monitored and controlled iterations of beta application, using open source version control software GIT to ensure efficient communication of project scope to project members
- Wrote code, using object-oriented programming, with PHP to create plugins for Wordpress websites and improve revenue through commercial distribution
- Improved responsiveness of website, using AngularJS RESTful web service to request product information;
- Parsed SQL and noSQL records using JSON to update user interfaces
- Carried out cross browser development using Bootstrap to reach more users by designing and developing UI's to adapt to the size of different browsers
- Carried out Behavioural Driven Development (BDD) using Mocha.js to reduce the number of errors while developing web applications
- Carried out Test Driven Development (TDD) using Jasmine.js to reduce the number of errors while developing web applications

Education

May 2016 – December 2016 Project Management Institute

PMI Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP)

September 2010 – November 2011 Kingston University

MSc Accounting and Finance (pass),

Modules studied include: Financial Accounting, Management Accounting, Corporate Strategy, Financial Reporting, Financial Management, Finance and Investment, Tax, Audit and Control, Dissertation.

September 04–June 08 Kingston University

BSc (Hons) Business Science with Computing (2:1)

Modules studied include: Fundamental programming concepts, Object-Oriented programming with Java, HTML Programming and Internet tools, Business Modelling, Web Technologies, Databases, Software Development with Java, XML for the web, Basic Visual Basic Programming, Advanced Visual Basic Programming, Systems Analysis and Design, Business Environment, Organisational Studies, Human Resource Management, Marketing Management, Accounting in Business Context, Business to Business Marketing, Decision Making, Corporate Strategy, Management Accounting

Technical Skills

 HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Express JS, Node JS, MongoDB, noSQL, JSON, XML, AJAX, Mocha.JS, Jasmine.JS, XHTML, PHP, MySQL, JQuery, GitHub, Objective C, Sublime Text Editor 2, Android SDK, Xcode, Eclipse, Adobe Creative Suite

Portfolio - http://machelslack.tumblr.com